<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the mayor the right honourable the lord mayor ... doth hereby think fit to publish and declare, that all manner of persons within this city and the liberties thereof, do from time to time duly observe and conform themselves to the laws and ordinances established for the suppression of abuses, disorders and misdemeanours ...</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1679</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A49070</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2885X</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R41297</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">31354839</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 31354839</idno>
            <idno type="VID">110273</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A49070)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 110273)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1745:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the mayor the right honourable the lord mayor ... doth hereby think fit to publish and declare, that all manner of persons within this city and the liberties thereof, do from time to time duly observe and conform themselves to the laws and ordinances established for the suppression of abuses, disorders and misdemeanours ...</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Clayton, Robert, Sir, 1629-1707.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>2 leaves.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Samuel Roycroft, Printer to the Honourable City of London,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1679.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Order for suppression of swearing, gaming, keeping bawdy-houses, etc. Text is the same as that of 23 December, 1672.</note>
                  <note>Broadside, divided in two leaves.</note>
                  <note>"Dated at Guildhal the 31 day of January in the 31 year of the reign of our Sovereign Lord Charles the Second ..."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Guildhall Library (London, England).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-08</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:110273:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms</figDesc>
               </figure>By the Mayor.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE Right Honourable the Lord Mayor (by and with the Advice of the Aldermen his Brethren) doth hereby think fit to publiſh and declare, That all manner of perſons within this City and the Liberties thereof, do from time to time duly obſerve and conform themſelves to the Laws and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinances eſtabliſhed for the ſuppreſſion of Abuſes, Diſorders and Miſdemeanours, and ſettlement of Peace, Order and Quiet amongſt his Majeſties Subjects: And that his Lordſhip doth purpoſe to uſe his beſt Care and Endeavour to inforce the Execution thereof, and inflict the utmoſt Penalties upon all ſuch perſons as ſhall be diſcovered to neglect or fail in their duty therein; And doth re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire all Citizens and Inhabitants, and more eſpecially all publick Officers to be aiding and aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſting for the diſcovery of all perſons that ſhall be found to practiſe and commit any manner of ſuch Diſorders and Enormities.</p>
            <p>And particularly his Lordſhip doth earneſtly admoniſh and command all Citizens and Inhabitants of this City deeply to conſider, examine and obſerve the points of their <hi>OATHS,</hi> as firſt the Oath of Supremacy, provided for Extirpation of the Romiſh Religion. Secondly, the Oath of Allegiance ordained for preſervation of the Honour and Fidelity due to his Majeſty. Thirdly, the Oath taken by all perſons admitted to the Freedom of this City, which for want of Conſideration is in many particulars and frequently infringed, and the good and neceſſary Franchiſes and Cuſtomes of this City there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by violated.</p>
            <p>That all perſons do refrain unneceſſary and profane <hi>SWEARING</hi> and <hi>CURSING</hi> in ordinary Converſe, for which the Penalty of Twelve pence is by the Law appointed to be paid or levied by way of Diſtreſs for every Offence, or (in caſe no Diſtreſs can he had) the Offender to ſit three hours in the Stocks.</p>
            <p>That no Vintner, Inn-keeper, Ale-houſe or Coffee-houſe-keeper do permit any <hi>SPORTING</hi> or <hi>TIPLING</hi> in their Houſes on the Lord's Day; nor any perſons meet there to ſport, tipple or uſe unlawful or unſeaſonable exerciſes, on the Penalties in that Caſe appointed by the Statutes of this Realm. And that no Herbs, Fruit or other things be expoſed to ſale, nor any
<pb facs="tcp:110273:2"/> Hackney Coachman ſtand and ply in the Streets on that Day. But that all perſons do ſeriouſly apply themſelves to the ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation of the ſaid Day, by exerciſing themſelves thereon in the duties of Piety and true Religion, publickly and privatly, according to the directions of a late Act of Parliament, and not waſting their time idly, and in unprofitable diſcourſes in Coffee-Houſes, of late too much practiſed.</p>
            <p>And that none do preſume to keep a Common Bawdy-Houſe or Gaming-Houſe for the reception of lewd and diſſolute per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, which have been obſerved to occaſion the ruine and deſtruction of many Apprentices and Young Men within this Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty: And that none do repair to any ſuch Houſes; or be a common Drunkard, or quarrelſome and a diſturber of the Peace, or a promoter of Strife and Variance between others: Which are all Offences againſt the Law, and to be puniſhed in ſuch manner as by the Law is directed.</p>
            <p>And that no perſon do keep any publick Houſe, or ſell Ale, Coffee or other like Liquors, unleſs they be duly Licenced for that purpoſe.</p>
            <p>And further that no Vintner, Brewer, Butcher, Baker or other do ſell any Bread, Wine, Beer, Fleſh or other Victual whatſoever, but ſuch only as ſhall be good and wholeſome for Mans Body.</p>
            <p>And all Bakers are to keep the Aſſize appointed: And that all Weights and Meaſures uſed in common Traffick ſhall be duly ſized and ſealed.</p>
            <p>And his Lordſhip doth hereby ſtraitly command all Conſtables to apprehend and take all ſorts of Beggers, idle and ſuſpected perſons, and if they ſee cauſe to make ſearch in any Victualing-houſe or other place ſuſpected to harbour ſuch looſe and ſuſpected people, and to carry them to <hi>Bridewel,</hi> as the Statute directs, wherein is contained alſo a Penalty for the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables neglect herein. And that the ſaid Conſtables do duly hold their Watches every night with their full num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers, and at the hours appointed, and ſuffer no perſons to paſs the Street at late and unſeaſonable hours, unleſs they can give a good account of themſelves and their occaſions.</p>
            <p>And his Lordſhip doth expect, That all manner of perſons within this City and Liberties, do in all particulars de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mean themſelves as becomes them within the bounds of Iuſtice, Sobriety and good Order, conceiving himſelf obliged in Duty, and for diſcharge of his Truſt, to inflict ſuch due Puniſhment upon all Criminals and Offenders, as the nature of their Offences ſhall require; and he doth expreſly charge all Conſtables and other his Majeſties Officers within this Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Liberties, and all Citizens of this City, (as they tender the good Government, Peace and Welfare thereof) to diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver and give Information either to his Lordſhip, the Court of Aldermen, or any of his Majeſties Iuſtices of the Peace within the ſaid City, of all perſons offending and misdemeaning themſelves, wherein they ſhall from time to time receive all due encouragement and countenance.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Dated at <hi>Guildhal</hi>
                  </hi> 
                  <date>the 31 day of <hi>January</hi> in the 31 year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord CHARLES the Second, by the Grace of God of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> King, Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <closer>God ſave the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>Samuel Roycroft,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of <hi>LONDON,</hi> 1679.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
